samanage.com 2017-09-15

# Privacy Policy | Samanage

_Effective date: April  24, 2017_

## Purpose

This privacy policy applies to www.samanage.com owned and operated by Samanage.

Samanage respects the privacy of anyone who uses a Samanage website ([www.samanage.com](https://www.samanage.com/)) or the Samanage Service. Samanage publishes this Privacy Policy to communicate how we gather and use information about you and how we protect it. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.  

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

## Information Related to Data Collected for our Customers

Samanage collects information under the direction of its customers, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. If you are a user of one of our customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our customers that use our service, please contact the customer that you interact with directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our customers.

Samanage acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Samanage has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct the query to the Samanage customer (the data controller). If the customer requests Samanage to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our customers for as long as needed to provide services to our customer. Samanage will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Information Collected

We require customers who use the Samanage service (Service) to give us contact information, such as their name, company name, address, phone number, and email address. At the time you express interest in receiving additional information or evaluating our service, or when you register for the Service, we may also ask for additional personal and company information, such as your role. Customers can opt out of providing this additional information by not entering it when asked. When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use and the operating system version.

Samanage uses the information collected to provision and deliver the Service for organizations. We may also use the information to contact customers to further discuss customer interest in our Service, and to send information regarding our company and our partners, such as marketing promotions, newsletters, and invitations to participate in events. Other than in connection with provision of the Service, customers can opt out of being contacted by us, or receiving such information from us, at any time by sending an email to support@samanage.com.

Except as stated at the time we request information, or as contemplated in this policy or the Samanage [Master Subscription Agreement](https://www.samanage.com/master-subscription-agreement/) or required by law, we do not disclose any personally identifiable information (including, without limitation, email addresses) that is provided by customers to third parties. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

Samanage may employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share customer information with them to provide the Services. Examples include billing, fulfilling orders, provisioning, sending emails, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU and Swiss individuals received pursuant to the EU-US and EU-Swiss Privacy Shield, Samanage is potentially liable.

We may utilize a tool that enables us to monitor visitors inputs (which includes mouse and keyboard actions), but we will only save information regarding the time and date of such inputs and the related input field. In addition, as part of the registration process, we will collect and store information filled out by you in the registration form, which may be later retrieved in case that the registration process was interrupted and needs to be reinitiated. We may also use this information to contact you for technical assistance reasons and/or sales purposes.

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to [www.samanage.com](https://www.samanage.com/).

## Protection of Company and Others

Samanage may release information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Samanage, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

We may choose to buy or sell assets during the normal course of business. Customer information can be one of the assets that are transferred. Moreover, if Samanage, or substantially all of its relevant assets, were acquired by merger, consolidation, sale of assets or otherwise, customer information would be one of the assets that would be transferred. You will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

## Customer Data

Customers using the Service will be storing data and information (Customer Data), and will connect the Service to customers’ computers using the Samanage Agent (Agent) for the purpose of collecting configuration and inventory data and storing data together with the Customer Data. Samanage will not review, share, distribute, print, or reference any Customer Data except as provided in this policy or in the Samanage [Master Subscription Agreement](https://www.samanage.com/master-subscription-agreement/) or as may be required by law, and except for the purposes of deploying, supporting or enhancing the Service. Customers are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of their user registration and password.

Samanage may also be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Samanage is subject to the investigative and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

Customers who are Covered Entities or Business Associates under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 as amended (“HIPAA”) must agree to comply with the HIPAA Privacy and Security Rules, including without limitation the Minimum Necessary Rule at 45 CFR 164.502(b). While Samanage has put safeguards in place consistent with those required by the HIPAA Privacy and Security Rules, because of the nature of Samanage service, Samanage does not expect to receive any Protected Health Information (PHI) from Covered Entities or Business Associates. Because Samanage does not review Customer Data, as set forth above, Customer understands and accepts that Samanage will not be able to provide the identities of individuals whose PHI is in Samanage’s system for any HIPAA reporting obligations.

Samanage may provide the ability for website visitor to request additional information or contact Samanage. We collect certain information from visitors such as their name, phone number and email and the purpose of their request or interest. This information is captured in our systems to better serve our customers and visitor needs. We also capture log information from our servers to help diagnose technical problems, and to constantly improve the quality of the Service. We may also track and analyze non-identifying and aggregate usage and volume statistical information from our website visitors and customers and provide such information to third parties.

## User Access and Choice

Upon request Samanage will provide customer with information about whether we hold any customer personal information. If customer personally identifiable information changes, or if the customer no longer desires our service, customer may update, change, amend and delete/remove registration information by going to the user or company profile record under the setup/administration section. To discontinue the Service customers should simply let a trial period expire. For paid subscription and if you need assistance in correcting, updating or deleting your information, please send your request to [support@samanage.com](mailto:support@samanage.com) or contact us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. Samanage will respond to your correction or update request within at most 30 days from the date of your request.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletters, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [support@samanage.com](mailto:support@samanage.com).

We may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). We use this information to improve our services. We may use a third party service provider to conduct surveys; that company will be prohibited from using our users’ personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

## Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

When you are using the Service we strive to make the service easy to use and valuable to you and your company. Samanage and our partners e.g. marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers (e.g. Zendesk, GetSatisfaction, etc) use cookies or similar technologies in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies for Marketing purposes, to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

We may work with a third party to either display advertising on our Website or to manage our advertising on other sites. That third party may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

## Third Party Sites

The Samanage Website or Service may contain links to other websites. Samanage is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites. Customers and visitors will need to check the policy statement of these other websites to understand their policies and how they protect their privacy. Customers and visitors who access a linked site may be disclosing their private information. It is the responsibility of the user to keep such information private and confidential. In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of European Union and Swiss individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield, Samanage is potentially liable.

## Blog and Community Forum

Our blog and community forum are managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog and community forum. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

## Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [support@samanage.com](mailto:support@samanage.com).

## Single Sign-On

You can log in to our site using sign-in service such as Facebook Connect and Google Apps. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Website to your profile page to share with others within your network.

## Social Media Widgets

Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Security

Samanage utilizes some of the most advanced technology for Internet security available today. When accessing our site using a common web browser, Secure Socket Layer technology is used across various parts of the site and protects your information using both server authentication and data encryption, ensuring that your data is safe and secure.

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can contact us at [support@samanage.com](mailto:support@samanage.com).

Samanage also provides each User in your organization with a unique password that must be entered each time a User logs into the Service. As stated above, Samanage is using a session “cookie” to store user sessions and provide an easy to use experience. Cookies do not include either the username or password of the user, or any other confidential user and session information.

Samanage is hosted in a security oriented server environment that uses a firewall and other advanced technology to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. [Learn more about our security practices](https://www.samanage.com/support/trust/) and how our service is protected.

## Opt-Out Policy

Samanage offers its website visitors and customers a means to choose how we may use information provided. If, at any time after registering for information or ordering the Service, you change your mind about receiving information from us, send us a request specifying your new choice. Simply send your request to [support@samanage.com](mailto:support@samanage.com).

## Changes to this Policy

Samanage will update this policy promptly if and when any of the policies described here changes. When we make material changes to this policy, we will post an announcement on our website with details prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## EU-US Privacy Shield Principles and Privacy Complaints

Samanage complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Samanage has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

In compliance with the US-EU and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Samanage commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Samanage at:

Email: [privacy@samanage.com](mailto:privacy@samanage.com)  
Physical Address:  
Attn: Samanage Privacy Office  
Samanage  
117 Edinburgh South,  
Suite 100  
Cary, NC 27511

Samanage has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint.

## Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework Principles and Privacy Complaints

Samanage complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Samanage has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the US-EU and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Samanage commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Samanage at:

Email: [privacy@samanage.com](mailto:privacy@samanage.com)  
Physical Address:  
Attn: Samanage Privacy Office  
Samanage  
117 Edinburgh South,  
Suite 100  
Cary, NC 27511

Samanage has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint.

## Additional Information:

Questions regarding this Statement or the practices of this site should be directed to the Samanage support team by sending your questions to [support@samanage.com](mailto:support@samanage.com).
